SUDHANSHU KULKARNI

🕲 DEV PROFILE . 🔘 sudhanshu.kulkarni.13@gmail.com . in linkedin.com/in/sudhanshu-kulkarni . 🗘 github.com/simplysudhanshu San Francisco, CA □ +(1) 609-721 1446

I am an earnest **Software Developer** with a perfect blend of the research-oriented and application-oriented portfolio. With years of experience facilitating clean & efficient software, I am currently exploring the realms of HPC and Quantum Computing; with a cup of coffee, of course.

EDUCATION

2024

MS - COMPUTER SCIENCE, San Francisco State University

THESIS: Benchmarking hybrid Classical-Quantum computing interaction models & exploring the associated challenges. 🗞 COURSE WORK: High-Performance Computing, Quantum Computing, Data Mining, Software Engineering

2020

BE - COMPUTER ENGINEERING, International Institute of Information Technology (SPPU)

CAPSTONE: Satellite data analysis system employing vanilla Neural Networks and Dynamic Time Warping algorithms, % COURSE WORK: Machine Learning & Al, Data Analytics, Cloud Computing, Cyber Security

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

Languages Frameworks Python, C/C++, Java, CUDA, TypeScript, Javascript, SQL, HTML/CSS, bash.

SENSEI, Qiskit, cuQuantum, Frappe, Django, Flask, SvelteJS, NodeJS, MySQL, NoSQL, Redis, Jira.

Git, Tensorflow, PyTorch, Keras, SciPy/NumPy, MPI/OpenMP, Linux, AWS, GCP, Docker/Kubernetes, nginx. Tools



EXPERIENCE

11/2022 - Present

Graduate Research Assistantship - San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA (1 yr, 6 mos)

- · Conducted feasibility studies on performing scalable FFT computations "in situ" on HPC platforms leveraging CPU, GPU & Quantum hardware to support scientific data analysis workloads in exascale NERSC projects like WarpX.
- · Collaborated with scientists at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (LBNL) to conduct research on Perlmutter (HPE Cray EX supercomputer), achieving a minimum of 10x speedup in computation time compared to traditional methods. Created a novel numerical FFT library for distributed-memory parallel architecture.

C++ Python High-Performance Computing Massively Parallel Open Source Scientific Computing MPI Cuda Quantum Computing

05/2023 - 08/2023

(3 mos)

SDE Intern - AMAZON WEB SERVICES, Seattle, WA

- · Prototyped a robust & lightweight monitoring service to ensure timely capturing and reporting of critical metrics, guaranteed to enhance service reliability by at least 10% after full-fledged deployment on thousands of live AWS servers worldwide as a part of the AWS CloudFront CDN services' platform team.
- · Curated live dashboards to provide real-time visibility into at least 70% of all the agents running on servers, empowering the team to actively maintain reliability and diagnose potential issues.

Python Server-side scripting Dashboarding Scalable Development Clean Coding Unit Tests Agile

08/2020 - 07/2022

Software Engineer - ELASTICRUN, Pune, IN

(2 yrs)

- · Core developer of in-house ERP system to manage large-scale logistics and B2B eCommerce platform and responsible for at least 20% of the entire development workload of the 'Velocity' segment of the company.
- · Executed heavy Python-based server-side development and business-focused client-side scripting for progressive web apps in an agile software development environment.
- · Developed an automated testing framework and handled bi-weekly live software deployments with Kubernetes and GitLab-based CI/CD pipelines, acquiring ≈15% improvement in deployment rate and reliability.

Python TypeScript Frappe Framework PWA SvelteJS Full stack Git CI/CD Technical Documentation

03/2018 - 07/2018

IoT Specialist Intern - SCMIND LLC, Princeton, NJ

(4 mos)

· Designed and implemented low-level code for IoT-enabled supply chain machinery firmware on Raspberry Pi microprocessor, enabling an 85% decline in unplanned downtime through real-time performance monitoring and sensorbased anomaly detection integrated via cloud pipeline feeding a global PowerBI dashboard.

Python | [IoT | Supply Chain | PowerBl | Microsoft Azure | AWS Redshift | Raspberry Pi | Performance Optimized |

NOTABLE EXPERIENCES

- · An integral member of the Early-Career Conference Review Board for the ISAV workshop at The Super-Computing conference (SC23), tasked with technical assessment of submitted research papers and complimented it with a noteworthy lightning talk on Scalable FFT project research. | Peer Reviewed Abstract from the conference: https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01843 %
- · Contributor to the Open Source SENSEI Project as a new FFT analysis backed endpoint.
- · Led GIS project to perform multi-class image classification on multi-spectral & temporal satellite data employing Deep Learning, Vanilla Neural Networks & signal-matching algorithms yeilding over 80% accuracy. Technical collaborations with scientists from Indian Space Research Organization (ISRO), NRSC & Geospatial Design Labs, India. %